sleepadvisor.org 2019-07-01

# Privacy Policy - The Sleep Advisor

We, Digitalpoint OÜ (Estonian company), as a controller of personal data, which is provided by you while using SleepAdvisor.org (the “Site”), have developed this Privacy Policy (the “Policy”) in order for you, our Site user, to understand how we collect, use, communicate and disclose your personal data, as well as for the purpose of obtaining your consent for advertising purposes . This Policy is part of our Terms of Service (the “Agreement”), located at [https://www.sleepadvisor.org/terms-conditions/](https://www.sleepadvisor.org/terms-conditions/), which is a legally binding contract.

**1 – Personal Data we collect**

Personal data means any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person (hereinafter “ **Data Subject** ”). An identifiable natural person is one who can be identified, directly or indirectly, in particular by reference to an identifier such as a name, an identification number, location data, an online identifier or to one or more factors specific to the physical, physiological, genetic, mental, economic, cultural or social identity of that natural person (hereinafter “ **Personal Data** ”).

For providing services of our Site (such as mattress quiz, mattress recommendations and reviews, downloading an e-book, participating in discussions in forum) we collect following Personal Data:

  * name; 
  * e-mail address; and
  * other information provided by you while answering mattress quiz on our Site and information provided by you in forum of our Site such as personal or professional interests, demographics, experiences with certain products or services.

For retargeting and marketing purposes we collect also tracking information such as your browser type, mobile device, the type of operating system you use, your IP address, the name of your Internet service provider, information related to any applicable domain names, and pages visited on the Site. 

**2 – Legal ground for using your Personal Data**

We process your Personal Data on the following legal grounds:

  * processing is necessary for the performance of the Agreement to which you are a party; and

  * by accepting this Privacy Policy, you give consent for the processing of your Personal Data for retargeting and marketing, including sending newsletters and advertisements.

**3 –  How information is collected**

In addition to prompting you for information, the Site uses technology to obtain tracking and personal information. We use cookies and web beacons, described below, to collect information about the pages you view, the links you click and other actions you take on the Site.  Additionally, we collect certain standard information your browser sends to every website you visit, such as your IP address, browser type and language, access times and referring website addresses. Most aggregate information is collected via cookies, web beacons and other technical methods. Web beacons, also known as clear gifs, in conjunction with cookies, are used to compile statistics about website usage. Web beacons are small pieces of data embedded in images on the pages of websites or applications. We may use these technical methods to analyze the traffic patterns on Site, such as the frequency with which our users visit various parts of the Site and to measure Site effectiveness or use of online products and services. We may also use Web beacons in HTML emails that we send our visitors who have agreed to receive email from us, to determine whether our recipients have opened those e-mails and/or clicked on links in those emails. On their own, cookies or Web beacons do not contain or reveal any personally identifiable information. However, if you choose to furnish us with personally identifiable information, this information can be associated to the data stored in the cookies or Web beacons. These technical methods may involve the transmission of information either directly to us or to product advertisers. These technical methods allow us to make the Site more interesting to you. You may render some Web beacons unusable by rejecting their associated cookies.

We also use cookies to store, and sometimes to track, user information. Cookies, by themselves, do not tell us your email address or other personally identifiable information unless you choose to provide this information to us by, for example, registering or subscribing to the Site. A cookie is a small amount of data that is sent to your browser from a Web server and stored on your computer’s hard drive. A cookie contains a unique number that allows the Site to recognize your computer. We use both temporary and persistent cookies; a temporary cookie tracks visitor activity during a session or visit and it expires when you close your browser. We use them to provide continuity for your visit as you visit Site pages. Persistent cookies allow us to keep track of your user name and password (if you are a subscriber) so you do not have to re-enter that information each time you visit. The Help function on most browsers contains information on how to set your browser to notify you before accepting cookies or to disable cookies entirely. However, if you do not accept cookies, you will not be able to take advantage of various features on the Site that are available to other visitors.

**4 – Use of information collected**

We use the information we collect to better understand your needs. Specifically, we use your information to help provide you information that may be of interest to you. Also, you agree that we may obtain and use for advertising purposes any and all data you provide to us, including Personal Data collected through the use of cookies and the like.  Your data may be provided to product merchants and/or other third parties for the purpose of displaying advertisements that may be of interest to you. We also use the information we collect to make the Site easier to use by eliminating the need for you to repeatedly enter the same information; to perform research and analysis aimed at improving the Site; and to display content and advertising that are customized to your interests and preferences.

**Your choice to opt-out** **.** If you wish to opt-out and revoke the consent you have provided to us by accepting this Policy, you must email us at contact@sleepadvisor.org and specifically state that you would like us to keep your Personal Data private.  Once we receive your email, we will attempt to delete whatever you may have provided us, but you will be denied access from viewing the Site in the future to help ensure that we do not process your Personal Data.

**First Party Cookies**

First-party cookies are cookies that we directly issue to users when users view our Site.  We use these cookies for basic website function purposes, such as allowing pages to load faster when you browse our Site, and for marketing purposes as explained above. 

If you prefer that we don’t use cookies when you visit us, [click here](https://www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies/clear-cookies-installed.html) for information on how to change settings and configure your browser to reject cookies.

**Third Party Cookies**

Third-party cookies are not issued by us.  They are cookies issued by a third-party, like Google, for example. We use Google Analytics Advertising Features and have enabled the demographics and interests feature.  Click here ([https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/2799357?hl=en](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/2799357?hl=en))  for more information.

If you would like to opt-out of third-party cookies, here are some options:

**Google provides a suite of tools to control its cookies:**

  * Google Analytics, which is a tool used to track and report website traffic, provides an out-out browser add-on that can be downloaded [here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).
  * Google Safety Centre has a tool where you can control the ads you see on Google and control the data used for serving ads to you. It can be found [here](https://www.google.com/safetycenter/tools/#!/).

**Browser-level cookie controls**

Most popular browsers allow you to manage cookie settings. These settings can usually be found in the ‘Settings’, ‘Options’ or ‘Preferences’ menu of your browser. We included the links below to help you find the settings for some common browsers.

  * Manage cookie settings in [Chrome](https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?co=GENIE.Platform%3DDesktop&hl=en) and [Chrome Android](https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?co=GENIE.Platform%3DAndroid&hl=en) and [Chrome iOS](https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?co=GENIE.Platform%3DiOS&hl=en)
  * Manage cookie settings in [Firefox](https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences)
  * Manage cookie settings in [Internet Explorer](https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies)
  * Manage cookie settings in [Microsoft Edge](https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-10-microsoft-edge-and-privacy)
  * Manage cookie settings in [Safari](https://support.apple.com/kb/ph21411?locale=en_US) and [Safari iOS](https://support.apple.com/en-gb/HT201265)

If you decide to opt-out from the use of cookies you can continue using the site but have in mind that **all other terms of use will still apply**.

**5 – Storage of Personal Data**

We will not preserve Personal Data longer than it is reasonably necessary for us to achieve the purposes for which Personal Data were collected, while complying with the applicable legislation for the period of data retention. 

Personal Data is stored in United States of America. According to General Data Protections Regulation 2016/679 of the European Parliament and of the council (GDPR) we have to inform you that data protections level in third countries might differ from data protection level in European Union. However, we confirm that we have taken all reasonable measures to protect Personal Data in United States of America.

**6 – Rights of the Data Subject**

You have the right:

  1. to be informed about the collection and use of your Personal Data by us. This information is shared with you through this Privacy Policy;
  2. of access to Personal Data that we process about you;
  3. to rectification of inaccurate Personal Data;
  4. to erasure of your Personal Data. However, this right only applies under certain circumstances and is not absolute;
  5. to restrict processing of Personal Data. However, this right only applies under certain circumstances and is not absolute;
  6. to move, copy or transfer your personal data;
  7. to object to the processing of Persona Data, if you find that processing is conducted in violation of your legitimate rights;
  8. withdraw your consent to process your Personal Data;
  9. not to be subjected to a decision based solely on automated processing, including profiling: (e.g. automated processing of Personal Data to evaluate certain aspects about you), which produces legal effects concerning you or similarly significantly affects you unless:
    * it is necessary for entering into, or performance of, a contract between us; or
    * it is authorized by law; or 
    * you provide your explicit consent; and 
  10. lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority and apply for remedy of your rights, if you consider that processing of your Personal Data infringes your rights and interests under applicable law.

**7 – Security**

We have appropriate technical and organizational measures in place to safeguard your Personal Data from loss, misuse, and unauthorised access, disclosure, alteration or destruction. 

Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. Accordingly, despite our efforts to protect your Personal Data, we cannot and do not ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us or any information we obtain from you as a result of your use of the Site. You transmit and receive all such information at your own risk. WE PROVIDE ANY AND ALL INFORMATION AND SERVICES ON AN “AS IS” BASIS AND GRANT NO WARRANTIES OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS, IMPLIED OR STATUTORY. WE SPECIFICALLY DISCLAIM ANY IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE, OR NON-INFRINGEMENT.

**8 – Third-party websites**

Links to third party websites are provided solely as a convenience to you. If you use these links you will leave the Site. We have not comprehensively reviewed all of these third-party websites and do not control and are not responsible for any of these websites, their content or their privacy policies. Thus, we do not endorse or make any representations about them, or any information, software or other products or materials found there or any results that may be obtained from using them. If you decide to access any of the third-party websites linked to the Site, you do this entirely at your own risk.

**9 – Updates to the Policy**

If there are updates to the terms of this Policy we will post the revision date below.

_Last updated on 02/18/2019_
